字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
EPISODE 4: A TRUE WARRIOR
第4集：真正的戰士
Don't get cocky!
別太囂張！
What is he?
他…他在哪裡？
Here he comes!
他來了！
What do we do, Bjorn?
表倫，我們該怎麼辦？
Oh, no! Bjorn is on a rampage!
糟了，表倫爆走了！
Stop him! The boat can't take it!
快阻止他，船會沉的！
You're asking for the impossible!
根本不可能阻止得了他！
How are we to stop that monster?
我們要怎麼阻止那種怪物？
Run! No one can stop him!
快跑！沒有人阻止得了他！
He ate a berserker mushroom.
他吃了狂戰士蘑菇
All that with his bare fists. He's more than a mere monster.
竟然徒手就打倒他…
The Troll… of Jom.
約姆的戰鬼
Just one ship to go.
只剩一艘船了
Here… they come.
他們來了
-What should we do? -Surrender?
-我們該怎麼辦？ -要投降嗎？
Damn it! We just have to fight!
可惡！我們只能迎戰了！
I'd rather die fighting than be enslaved!
我寧可死也不要被變成奴隸！
Listen up. We're taking them alive.
聽好了，我們要活捉他們
They're worth less when injured.
他們受傷的話可賣不了好價錢
Be gentle with them.
小心點
Time we have a little fun.
玩耍時間到了
Bjorn?
表倫？
Thors!
托爾茲！
Listen!
聽好了！
Your fighting strength has already been halved.
你們的戰力已經減半了
Retreat and keep your lives.
撤退保命吧
Leave, pirates!
離開吧，海盜
You cannot win against me.
你們打不過我的
Bastard.
混蛋…
Stop. We can't shoot until Askeladd gives the signal.
住手，要等阿謝拉特打信號 我們才能放箭
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
We've got the high ground.
我們有制高點這個優勢
What's he waiting for?
他還在等什麼？
What an astounding man.
真是可怕的男人
He's standing his ground against two ships all by himself.
他一個人對抗兩艘船艦
Leif, we should fight too!
雷夫，我們也該戰鬥！
Fool! You amateurs will only get in the way.
笨蛋！你們這些外行人只會礙事
There are arrows aimed at us from above.
上面可是有人拿箭瞄準我們
He's the most experienced among us.
托爾茲是我們之中最有經驗的
Don't you get it?
你不懂嗎？
Unlike Thors, we're just a bunch of children and amateurs.
除了托爾茲之外 我們只是一群小鬼、外行人
All we can do is rely on him.
我們只能靠他了
These men aren't the type to leave quietly when asked.
這些人不會聽話離開的
For now, the archers on the cliff won't shoot.
懸崖上的弓箭手暫時不會放箭
There's roughly 30 men. That's too many for me to handle alone.
前方大約有30個人
The ships are too close.
船之間的距離很窄
If they jump over all at once, the fight will be chaotic.
他們一次跳過來的話 肯定會爆發混戰
If only I were alone.
只有我一個人倒還好，但是…
You're the leader.
你就是首領？
In the name of almighty Odin,
在全能的奧丁神見證下
I challenge you to a duel.
我要向你下決鬥戰帖
A duel?
單挑？
If you win, you may do as you wish.
如果你贏了，我們任你處置
If I win, you will promptly withdraw your men.
如果我贏了，你們就立刻撤兵
If you refuse,
要是你拒絕
you will gain a mere 12 slaves while losing three times that of your men.
你就會為了12個奴隸，失去36個手下
May I ask a question?
可以問個問題嗎？
Why do you assume I'm the leader?
你怎麼會認為我是首領？
Your scent.
因為氣味
Very impressive.
很厲害嘛
All right. I accept your challenge.
好吧，我接受挑戰
I, Askeladd, son of Olaf, swear it in the name of Odin!
我，沃拉夫之子阿謝拉特 以奧丁神之名發誓
Everyone, move to the bow of the ship.
大家都退到船頭去
All right.
好
I, too,
我啊
knew you by your scent.
也從你的氣味認出了你
You and I have the same smell.
你和我有同樣的味道
Troll of Jom.
約姆的戰鬼
He knows me?
他認識我？
It was Floki.
弗洛基嗎？
You have good intuition.
你的直覺很準
I like smart people.
我喜歡聰明人
Don't you dare think that you're the same as my father!
別把我爸和你相提並論
Enough. Get back!
夠了，退後！
My father is strong!
我爸很強！
Die, pirate!
去死吧，海盜！
You're stupid and your armor's weird!
你很蠢，你的盔甲也很怪！
What a lively little brat. Your son?
真是活潑的小鬼，他是你兒子嗎？
Enough, you idiot. Stop it.
夠了，你這笨蛋，住手
Askeladd, do you have a wife and children?
阿謝拉特，你有妻小嗎？
No.
沒有
I see.
這樣啊
Let's begin.
我們開始吧
He's awfully casually closing the gap between us.
他隨隨便便就縮小我們之間的距離
Too shallow!
太淺了
That's our leader!
真不愧是首領！
There's no one who can match Askeladd!
沒人打得過阿謝拉特！
Father!
爸爸！
He managed to dodge certain death.
被他閃過了必殺的時機
I won't be able to surprise him again.
看來突襲對他沒有用了
It was worth coming all this way to this remote land.
我大老遠跑來這偏遠的地方 真是沒有白來
He's no ordinary man.
他很不簡單
Thors.
托爾茲
You're strong.
很厲害嘛
Give it up, Askeladd.
放棄吧，阿謝拉特
I won't go easy on you.
我不會手下留情
I'm glad I met you, Thors.
很高興認識了你，托爾茲
What?
什麼？
Amazing. He's overwhelming him!
好厲害，托爾茲把他壓著打
Is Askeladd in trouble?
阿謝拉特有麻煩了嗎？
He's still defending against every blow.
但他還是把攻擊全都擋住了
Father!
爸爸！
Kill that scoundrel!
幹掉那個無賴！
Oh, no.
糟了
He was aiming for my sword?
他的目標是我的劍？
It can't take much more.
劍撐不住了
Which means his sword is also at its limit.
這就表示他的劍也不行了
Now!
就是現在！
I know where he's aiming,
我知道他瞄準哪裡
so I can predict the swing of his sword!
所以也能預測他的劍會落在哪！
Now he'll swing wide!
他會大動作揮劍
He got me.
中計了
He wanted me to swing big to catch me off guard.
他在等我掉以輕心，大動作揮劍
He wanted me to break his sword.
他要我砍下他的劍尖
Everything went as he'd predicted.
全都如他所料
Damn.
可惡
To think I'd played right into his hands.
我竟然中了他的計
Yes!
好耶！
Thors!
托爾茲！
-Amazing! -That's my father!
-太棒了！ -不愧是爸爸！
He won!
他贏了！
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Kill me.
殺了我
There is no need for that.
沒必要這樣
Concede defeat. That is enough.
認輸就夠了
I'm the leader, you know.
我可是首領
I can't surrender in front of my men.
我不能在手下面前認輸
What's wrong? Kill me.
怎麼了？動手啊
This duel will never end unless you kill me.
殺了我才能結束這場決鬥
My head hurts.
我的頭好痛
What?
什麼？
What's happening?
發生什麼事？
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特竟然…
Lost.
輸了
He lost?
他輸了？
Admit it.
認輸吧
I have won this duel.
這場決鬥是我贏了
Withdraw your soldiers now!
立刻撤兵
You're truly strong, Thors.
你真的很強，托爾茲
You're worthy of leading your own army.
你甚至有資格帶領自己的軍隊
But why?
但是為什麼？
With skills like that, why hide in Iceland for 15 years?
你能力非凡 為什麼卻在冰島躲了15年？
Don't you think it's a waste?
不覺得太可惜了嗎？
I do not.
我不覺得
Having to rely on something like this…
我得仰賴這種東西
means I still have much to learn.
就表示我要學的還有很多
A true warrior needs no sword.
真正的戰士不需要劍
Thors, would you…
托爾茲，你…
become our leader?
要不要當我們的首領？
I'm joking!
開玩笑的啦
Come on, why is no one laughing?
喂，為什麼沒人笑？
It was a joke.
我開玩笑的啦
What was that? Just a joke?
什麼？開玩笑？
This isn't the time
現在不是開玩笑的時候
to be joking with a straight face!
而且還一臉嚴肅！
None of you move!
你們都不准動！
I'll slice the kid's head right off!
不然我就砍了這小子的頭！
Drop your sword!
把劍丟掉！
Do it quickly!
快點！
Askeladd, you bastard!
阿謝拉特，你這個混蛋！
Father!
爸爸！
My goodness, you are soft-hearted.
天啊，你真心軟
Did you really think we'd respect the rules of the duel?
你真的以為我們會遵守決鬥規則嗎？
We just wanted to have a little fun.
我們只是想找點樂子
We wanted to see who the Troll of Jom was for ourselves.
我們想看大名鼎鼎的約姆的戰鬼 到底是什麼樣的人
It was fun.
很有意思嘛
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
You've violated the rules of the duel.
你違反了決鬥的規則
Victory belongs to me.
這場決鬥是我贏了
It doesn't matter.
無所謂
I'm only after your head.
我的目的是取你的命
I know.
我知道
All right.
好吧
This victory…
這場決鬥
is yours.
是你贏了
Father!
爸爸！
Father…
爸爸…
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
I've won this duel.
這場決鬥是我贏了
Do not go against your word as a warrior.
你必須遵守身為戰士的約定
I know.
我知道
In the name of my ancestor Artorius, I'll withdraw my soldiers immediately.
我以我的祖先阿圖瑞斯之名發誓
Leif.
雷夫
Sorry, but I need a favor.
抱歉，但我要拜託你一件事
Take my head to Sigvaldi, the leader of the Jomsvikings.
把我的腦袋 交給約姆的首領希古瓦爾帝
If they think I avoided the call of war and hid once more,
如果他們以為 我為了逃避召集令又躲起來
they will take vengeance on the village.
村子會遭到報復的
How could this happen to you.
你怎麼這麼傻…
You there.
還有你
I've given my life as you wanted.
我如你所願付出性命了
Release that child now!
快放開那個孩子！
Father!
爸爸！
Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
You're safe for now.
至少你沒事了
Foolish brat.
臭小鬼
Cherish your life from now on.
從今以後你要珍惜性命
Be grateful to Thors.
感謝托爾茲吧
His death is worth more than a hundred of you worthless bastards.
你們這些沒用的混蛋來一百個 也不值他一條命
Father is dead.
爸爸死了
He was so strong.
他明明那麼強
Why did he throw his sword?
他為什麼要把劍丟掉？
How could he say warriors need no swords?
他怎麼能說戰士不需要劍？
That's not true at all!
才不是那樣！
Why?
為什麼…
Why did Father have to die?
為什麼爸爸…
Damn it.
可惡
Damn it!
可惡！
How could he live when father's dead?
為什麼爸爸死了，他卻還活著？
Damn it.
可惡
Damn it!
可惡！
They abandoned such a nice ship.
他們拋棄了一艘好船
What a drastic decision.
真是極端的決定
Without Thors, they couldn't move it.
少了托爾茲，他們划不動這艘船
He alone could row for five men.
他一個人就頂了五個人
But it worked out well for us since we wanted a third ship.
但對我們來說正好
Twenty-eight are injured, but how many are dead?
28人受傷，但有多少人死亡？
None?
沒有人死？
Not one? That's impossible!
一個都沒有？不可能！
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
Hey!
喂！
Come to the stern!
過來船尾！
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
What is it? Shut up already.
什麼事？吵死了
It's Thors's kid.
是托爾茲的孩子
He must've been hiding below deck.
他一定躲在甲板下面
Look. He's even got a grown-up's dagger.
你看，他還拿了大人的短劍
He's coming to kill us all!
他要來殺我們了！
Oh, no! I'm so scared!
不要，人家好害怕！
How dare you.
你竟然…
How dare you kill my father!
你竟敢殺我爸！
I'll kill you!
我要殺了你！
I swear I'll kill you!
我發誓我會殺了你！
I'll kill you!
我會殺了你！
He's just a kid,
他只是個孩子
but look at those eyes.
但看看那雙抓狂的眼睛
What should we do with him, Askeladd?
阿謝拉特，我們該拿他怎麼辦？
Throw him overboard?
把他丟下船？
Let him be.
別管他了
He'll be dead soon anyway.
反正他也活不了多久
Father.
爸爸…